Santoshkumar Sharma

Senior Consultant- Dot Net

421201, IN

santoshkumarsharma354_bky@indeedemail.com

+91-9594890953

Seeking an opportunity to work, as Project Manager, with the industry in a challenging environment that provides me an opportunity to learn and contribute in an effective manner towards the success of the organization.

- Having 7.4 years of total Experience and working as Technical Lead.
- Experience in Handling Team and all Project Management Activity
- Have experience in all the phases of software development starting from requirement gathering which involved dealing with the clients, until the final deployment of the web application at the application server.
- Executing project from Onsite (Netherland) for 2 months and got Recognition from the Client for the same.
- Awarded with "BRAVO award" an annual award of Capgemini for my performance in handling the team with involving in complex issues
- Awarded with "Extra mile award" from client for handling and supporting the project out of box with regular activity
- Worked extensively with C# / ASP.NET, MVC (BASIC) Controls, Ajax Toolkit, Dataset, Data Table and Data Reader as part of ADO.net to access and update the database.
- Good experience in handling data from multiple tables involving complex multi-table queries within stored procedures.
- Self -starter, highly motivated, able to operate under any circumstances, both self-managed or team environments.
- Improvised critical thinking, communication, and logical problem solving skills.
- Good grasping power, Team Spirit, Adaptability
- Taking ownership and responsibility.

Work Experience

Consultant

MENTION IN REVERSE CHRONOLOGICAL ORDER - NL

June 2018 to Present

Roles performed

This project was executed from Client Location (Netherland), As I was Leading this project and deputed to onsite for 2 Months. It was an Agile Project

- Attending SCRUM Meeting
- Interaction with Customer and End User
- Preparing Documentation
- Development and coordinating with Offshore Team
- · Working on Bug Fixes and Change request

Project Details Code base C#, WCF, LINQ, Visual Basic 6.0, MS Access Database SQL Server, SSIS, SSRS IDE Visual Studio 2008/2010/2013 Description

The Core Functionality of the application was to create Invoice .CSV file which include all the invoice details with VAT Information. This file used to create whenever any Invoice is created and credited. Once the file is created it is placed on SFTP Server (Secure FTP) .A respective notification is send on the file status to the user and NAV Tax Authority (Hungary). Error Handling with notification was taken care.

Sr. Consultant

Capgemini India Private Limited February 2017 to Present

Sr.No Organization Name From To 1 Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. 16-Feb 2017 Till Date

Consultant

MENTION IN REVERSE CHRONOLOGICAL ORDER February 2017 to Present

From 16 Feb 2017 Project Name Canon Venlo - MOB To Till Date Client Canon, Netherlands Role Consultant Roles performed

- Working on support tickets.
- Interacting with end-users as needed.
- Allocating Change Request and Tickets within Team
- Development with the New requirement

Code base ASP.NET MVC, C#, WCF, LINQ, Visual Basic 6.0, MS Access Database SQL Server IDE Visual Studio 2008/2010 Description

MOB is basically meant for Order creation, Contract creation with machine Configuration. This application involves many complex reports with live status of the available items.

This system also deals with the Invoicing part which can be user dependent and automation both. While doing the invoice the data is validated and Process from another application known as BlackBox application. The Black Box application basically created using a WCF services which is integrated as Windows Services which run on interval of every 5 minutes. It validates the Invoices by some Special XML template which is created on based of the invoice types. Once the XML is validated it is passed to the third party Exact Exe which pass the XML file as a Parameter and the Data is loaded into the Globe (Exact) database.

Organization Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd. From 16 Feb 2017 Project Name FACIT To Till Date Client Canon, Netherlands Role Consultant Roles performed

- · Working on support tickets.
- Interacting with end-users as needed.
- Allocating Change Request and Tickets within Team
- Development with the New requirement and Deployment
- Creating Monitoring tools and Application.

Technology used in project Code base ASP.NET, .NET 4.0, 4.5 C#, Entity Framework, WCF, LINQ, Itextsharp, Console application, Chart controls Database SQL Server 2008 R2, 2012 IDE Visual Studio 2012 Description

It is a purely Invoicing application which also include manipulation and import-export of Master data which are somewhat pre request of the any invoicing. From this application User can manipulate the Master data, validate it using the functionality.

Once the Invoicing is done, the respective invoice is either created in XML format or PDF format as per the service user has selected while creating the order.

There are many interfaces are maintained which used to Posted the Invoice data to different System like SAP, AS400 and Oracle. The reason for posting the data to different System is of the broad Landscape of this system, as there are many more system which use this invoice data as input in there system.

Team Lead/Senior Software Engineer

Larsen & Toubro InfoTech January 2015 to Present

From 01 Jan 2015 Project Name STAR TRAC (Payroll Application)
To 10 Feb 2017 Client UTC Climate, Controls & Security Carrier, USA
Role Team Lead/Senior Software Engineer
Roles performed

- Coordinating with the onshore team for prioritizing production issues and status reporting.
- Leading the enhancement team on technical and functional fronts.
- Reviewing the support and enhancement tasks performed by the team

Technology used in project Code base ASP.NET, .NET 4.0, 4.5 C#, Entity Framework, WCF, LINQ, Itextsharp, Console application, Chart controls
Database SQL Server 2008 R2, 2012
IDE Visual Studio 2012
Description

This is a Carrier project. This website is calculation pay roll of the technician in carrier organization according to their working hours which they feed in a PDA device. Our Application used to get those data weekly from an Antenna database which is a device where the technician data is stored. Its involved Complex PDF record

Team Lead/Senior

Larsen & Toubro InfoTech March 2013 to Present

From 25 Mar 2013 Project Name SMART SERVICES
To 31 Dec 2014 Client UTC Climate, Controls & Security Carrier, USA
Role Team Lead/Senior Software Engineer
Roles performed

- Requirement Gathering and start to end communication and follow-up with client
- Actively participate in coding, customization (ATK based), unit testing, code review
- Development and always understanding client's requirement with implementing its to their expectation
- Status reporting to the project management.
- Involving in the R&D part for some new complex feature implementation

Technology used in project Code base ASP.NET, .NET 4.0, 4.5 C#, Entity Framework, WCF, LINQ, Itextsharp, Console application, Chart controls

Database SQL Server 2008 R2, 2012

IDE Visual Studio 2012

Description

This is a Carrier project. This website monitors the chillers efficiency. It stores details in cloud storage and periodically fetches the information using WCF Service into database. It also sends email notification if chiller is not efficient which is calculated by some predefined measurements. Admin can create user and assign a role and chiller or site.

There is also and console application which is part of this application, it helps to get the data from cloud.

It is a Console Application which is schedule in Windows scheduler which runs in interval of Every 15 minutes. This application communicates with a Cloud and fetch data from the cloud also load these data into SQL Server. It checks the Cloud in every 15 minutes whether any fresh data has been received or not. If yes, then load data into SQL server from the Cloud.

Technology Specialist

PMAM IT Services July 2012 to Present

From 01 Jul 2012 Project Name Centralized Information Document To 18 Mar 2013 Client SCB (STANDARD CHARTER BANK)

Role Technology Specialist Roles performed

- Participated in requirement discussion with project manager and team lead
- As this project has to be developed and deployed in client location, so coordinating with the infra team for proper deployment and access level issue
- Properly understanding the requirement after discussion with team lead and creating the document
- Implementation with proper unit testing which include resolution of issue which got tracked in the testing
- Deployment of the application on Prod environment.
- Working on the enhancement which has been requested by the user with proper request documentation

Technology used in project Code base ASP.NET 3.0, 3.5 C#, Chart Controls Database SQL Server 2008 R2 IDF Visual Studio 2005

Description

This is a web based Application used to maintain their Contracts and their documents, using this application user can add, modify and delete the contract with proper alerts and notification to the clients.

There was a separate screen in the application where user can set specific email template for the different clients with their provided template, which they can update any time

This application consists of a dashboard which helps to understand you overall contracts created, new renewal and expired contracts with the respective years with a user interactive charts. It helps them to analysis their business growth

These charts help them to increases business efficiency by analyzing the charts reports and functionality provided by this chart.

Technology Specialist

PMAM IT Services

December 2011 to Present

From 07 Dec 2011 Project Name PMAM Smart Select (Online Recruitment and Staffing Solution) To 30 June 2012 Client PMAM Product

Role Technology Specialist

Roles performed

- · Participated in requirement discussion with project manager and team lead
- Properly understanding the requirement after discussion with team lead and creating the document
- Implementation with proper unit testing which include resolution of issue which got tracked in the testing
- Deployment of the application on Prod environment.
- Working on the enhancement which has been requested by the user with proper request documentation

Technology used in project Code base ASP.NET 3.5, C#, Chart Controls, FTP Connection, FLV Player Database SQL Server 2008 R2 IDE Visual Studio 2008

Description

- This is a Recruitment and Staffing solution. This is highly functional and innovative recruitment software.
- This web application streamlines, automates and optimizes every feature and phase of your recruitment process.
- It helps you to post your job on the portal, purchase the candidates, and schedule the interviews for the candidates and all.
- It helps your hiring function come a full circle.

L&T InfoTech March 2013 to February 2017

Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd December 2011 to March 2013

Organization Capgemini India Pvt. Ltd.

Education

Bachelor Of Engineering in Computers

Mumbai University - Mumbai, Maharashtra August 2011

HSC

Mumbai University - Mumbai, Maharashtra March 2005

SSC

Mumbai University - Mumbai, Maharashtra March 2003

ADDRESS OF UNIVERSITY

Skills / IT Skills

- ASP (8 years)
- ASP.NET (8 years)
- C# (8 years)
- DATABASE (8 years)
- MS ASP (8 years)

Additional Information

Competencies

Web Tools ASP.NET, ASP.NET MVC 4/3 (BASIC), WCF, Web Service, IIS 7.0/6.0 Modeling Tools Visio 2003

Languages C#, VB MS ACCESS, VB 6.0 JavaScript, query, JSON, HTML, XHTML, XML Database SQL Server 2000/2005/2008/2008-R2, SSIS, SSRS Reporting Third Party Tools Entity Framework, Infragistics Controls, ItextSharp Pdf, WINSCP Sharp Operating Systems Windows 2000/Xp/2003/7, Window Server 2003/2008 R2 Version Control Microsoft VSS, TFS

Domain Experience

- Human Resource
- Payroll & Invoice
- Media & Entertainment
- Device & Instrumental